so it takes a while to actually start up
I don't want to start speaking so today
I want to talk about thinking versus
learning so learning is the external act
of putting other people's thinking into
your head whether that's watching
documentaries or reaping it's getting
new thoughts into your head and for me
that was the focus for the four-ton made
my 20s my late teens and 20s I was
focused on learning as much as I could
at history and science and economics and
business and psychology and self-help
and just everything that I was
interested in because I had this idea
that with enough information I would be
able to save the world to do something
that like knowledge is where it was at
and then I was given the gift of brain
tumors and brain surgery and radiation
and all of these things that came
together and greatly diminished my
ability to learn new external
information I still can but I can't
force it I never had the skill to to
really study like other people seem to
be able to do in university and cram
knowledge and I think I ever had that
ability but I would read it through one
so I would memorize it and it would just
be there and now I don't have that
ability so the difference now is I have
all of this time but I don't have the
ability like before I would just like
read a book watch a documentary then go
on to the next thing and I wouldn't
really ever master anything but it was
just this constant curiosity and feeding
this constant curiosity and there's zero
wrong with that but if I hadn't been
given the necessity to change because my
brain changed had no option but to I
wouldn't have found my purpose on in
life which is thinking and thinking and
is more using the information you
already have to come up with new ideas a
new problem something so anything it's
I'm pulling on all of my external
knowledge everything I've learned about
economics and history and
politics and everything but it's new
it's not someone else's idea it comes
from from within and there's a lot of
differences between the two but my
biggest thing is that I don't even like
I wouldn't be able and that that I'm so
stuck on I don't know that therefore I
crammed in so I could never be able to
say that it's still there because it's
the permanent thought in my head I don't
know I don't know all of the information
on that topic so now that I'm not able
to learn the external information as
easily my mind's created oh it's like we
still want access to the external
information so I want to make the
external information available to
everyone so it's available to me so you
don't have to necessarily put it in your
brain it's there ready to use visually
so that history is able to come alive
and people who aren't great at learning
history which I'm not the names and
dates just don't stick but people's
stories do so hearing people's stories
and seeing them played out in like
period pieces on film speak to me more
than any history class ever could and so
I want to bring history to life with
with technology I want to bring science
to life for people with technology and
that involves it doesn't mean everyone
has to know science and everyone has to
know history it means if you're
interested regardless of your belief in
your intellectual capacity or your
actual intellectual capacity you have
the ability to learn it so it's not
going to be a one-size-fits-all it's
going to be visual and hands-on and
learning in groups and putting the
information together and nobody has to
do all of that the beauty is somebody
will do each piece of it because it's
something that calls to them so people
who love history and want it to come
come alive for people people who want to
do the storytelling people who want to
do the visual graphics of making
timelines and having them be beautiful I
want to allow others to truly give their
knowledge so because even when I was
obsessed with the learning part of
information it doesn't really help
because I'm still arguing the facts with
somebody who doesn't have that
information so either trust me or they
don't
and I either have right information or I
don't if we can organize all of that and
have it accessible then we can stop
having the same old tired debate and
start actually doing the thinking and
create the solutions together I want to
give humanity because I want to give it
to me all access to all of the
information from data which is really
important to people who want data and
that's like the the cells the molecules
of information the actual like what
we're basing and then the statistics and
the discussions all the way up to like
the visual representation of the entire
subject and what we know today in a way
that's useable to people and together we
can do that it doesn't mean everyone
needs access to the data in an
intellectual capacity they just need
physical access to the data because the
data geeks are going to turn that into
discussions because that's what they
enjoy are going to turn that into visual
representations because that's what
those people enjoy and together we can
have a world designed on thinking and
when there is this external knowledge
it's not stopping our progress because
it's not like we have to have the same
old tired debate so that's today's topic